RYAN HENDRICKS

Cyber Security Professional • Technical Educator • Enablement Specialist

Tenacious Quest for Success and Learning. I am a Certified EC-Council Instructor (CEI), and CompTIA Certified Technical Trainer with more than 11 years of experience in education focusing on cyber security, information technology, and networking. Firmly believe that education and enablement overcome most challenges.

Results-Driven Leadership. Experienced Project Manager with IT experience. Skills include analytical thinking and creative problem solving. Able to apply best practices to improve business operations and performance.

Challenger of Conventional Wisdom. Always ask the WHY. Improve user experience through smart, strategic thinking that anticipates outcomes. Present use cases that influence, and lead change driving efficiency and profitability.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, 2014

| Major: Information Technology-Security

Western Governors University

Associate of Arts, 2009

Major: Arabic

Defense Language Institute Foreign Language Center (DFIFLC)

CERTIFICATIONS

VMware

VCTA Security - Sep 2020

(ISC)2

CISSP - 490481 - Oct 2014

EC-Council

CEI - Jan 2016

CEHv8 - Jun 2015

CompTIA

Linux+ - Mar 2015

CTT+, Classroom - Sep 2013

CASP+ - Mar 2013

Project+ - Dec 2012

Security+ - Aug 2011

Network+ - Jun 2011

Microsoft

MCSA, Windows 7 - Apr 2014

CIW

Database Design Specialist - Apr 2013 JavaScript Specialist - Oct 2012 Web Design Specialist - Jul 2012 Web Foundations Associate - May 2012

WORK EXPERIENCE

VMware

Staff Architect and Manager, Technical Content Solutions / Nov 2020 - Present

- Lead the team responsible for defining, evaluating, scoping, building, and updating technical education content covering VMware Carbon Black products, VMware security portfolio, and VMware vRealize suite.
- Design both classroom and eLearning content and collaborate with business stakeholders.
- Selected as a Subject Matter Expert for the initial security certifications within VMware.

Carbon Black - Acquired by VMware in 2019

Training Manager / Dec 2016 - November 2020

- Led a global team of 7 trainers providing training to over 4,000 learners annually.
- Drove business operations and delivery to maintain over 50% margins on training revenue.
- Maintained an individual trainer CSAT score of 96% and a team CSAT score of 95%.
- Delivered private virtual and private onsite training to several high visibility customers and adapted training delivery for partner specific use cases, requests, and needs.
- Main administrator for the Learning Management System, responsible for troubleshooting user technical issues, updating curriculum, and documenting all processes for consistency.
- Collaborated with Engineering, Marketing, Systems Engineering, and Professional Services to educate the enablement team on upcoming product features, functionality, and use cases.
- Selected by management to provide several technical presentations to large audiences at company user conferences, employee kickoffs, and regional security meetups.
- Reduced professional development costs by organizing and delivering employee technical enablement sessions on the Certified Ethical Hacker certification content.

Associate Advisor, Partner Consulting and Sustainment (Apr 2016 – Nov 2016)

- Worked with peers to adapt white-paper topics for the EDR certification into customer, employee, and partner enablement content using PowerPoint, Snagit, and Camtasia.
- Spearheaded the initial creation of all Cloud Endpoint Standard technical training content.
- Volunteered for on-site national and international training engagements.

Self-Employment

Technical Editor (Nov 2019 – Aug 2021)

 Independent contractor providing all technical edits for the CompTIA CASP+ Practice Tests CAS-003 & CAS-004 books by Sybex. Technical editor for previous and current version of the book. Includes over 1,000 questions covering all exam domains.

RYAN HENDRICKS

SKILLS

| Technical Expertise

EDR App Control NGAV UTM Windows 7/8/10 Server 08/12/16 Linux (Debian/RedHat) Kali Linux Virtualization Cloudshare Metasploit NMAP/HPING Wireshark SFT ZAP SQL TCP/IP JavaScript OSPF/EIGRP/BGP DNS DHCP Powershell Python HTML/CSS

Content Creation

Camtasia Snagit
Captivate uPerform
Word PowerPoint

| Enablement Delivery

Zoom WebEx GoToMeeting GoToWebinar Moodle VidYard

Collaboration

Slack Teams Flowdock Asana

REFERENCES

References available upon request

WORK EXPERIENCE

EPS, Corporation

Senior Technical Trainer (Oct 2013 – Apr 2016)

- Delivered CompTIA Network+, Security+, Linux+, CASP, CEH, CCENT, CCNA Routing and Switching, CCNA Security, CISSP and Army Cyber Security training courses.
- Maintained three separate professional training certifications: Certified EC-Council Instructor (CEI), Cisco Certified Academy Instructor (CCAI), and CompTIA Certified Technical Trainer (CTT+).
- Led the development team for the CCENT, CCNA Routing and Switching, and CCNA Security courses. Created physical hands-on and virtual labs, slides, and training assessment materials.
- Author of a hands-on lab guide for the Certified Ethical Hacker course including 100+ lab tasks.
- Responsibilities included maintaining hardware, software, network, and security functionality, managing the ESXi server, and administering the Learning Management System, Moodle.
- Instructed 37 courses totaling 500+ personnel maintaining a 77% certification pass rate. Training Manager (Aug 2012 Sep 2013)
- Responsible for a three person training team, provided logistical and administrative support.
- Oversaw the successful delivery of 87 different training events encompassing over 4,000 hours of instruction to more than 1,000 attendees.

LNO, Inc.

Instructor (May 2011 - Aug 2012)

- Trained CompTIA Network+, Security+, Windows7, CCENT, and CCNA courses.
- Instructed 15 classes totaling 236 personnel maintaining a 54% certification pass rate.

InovaTech

Instructor (Jan 2010 - May 2011)

- Trained CCENT, CCNA, and various Army network specific courses.
- Revised the CCNA course and created the CCENT course, improving the quality of instruction and allowing students to have hands-on and virtual labs.

United States Navy

Linguist (Jan 2004 - Jan 2010)

- Training Non-Commissioned Officer in Charge (NCOIC) responsible for initial training of Subject Matter Expert Linguists to establish proficiency in both language skills and job functionality.
- Deployed 127 days on board two United States naval vessels, performing cryptologic support operations at sea in support of Fleet and National Intelligence requirements.

EVENT TALKS / WEBINARS / PRESENTATIONS

Wild West Hackin Fest Wild West Hackin Cast VMworld
Conference 2021 Webinar 2020 2020

CB Connect Holiday Threats Intersection of SLED & Tech
2016-2021 Webinar 2020 Webinar 2020

CERT Star Fileless Attacks BlackHat
Rome 2019 Webinar 2019 Las Vegas 2019